ANA PINEDA

◆ CATERING AND EVENTS MANAGER ◆

anapineda12@icloud.com ♦ www.linkedin.com/in/anamichellepineda ♦ +949 556 7398

PROFILE

Highly organized Catering and Events Manager with the ability to multi-task in a fast-paced work environment. Experienced in creating mutually beneficial relationships with clients and vendors through constant customer service ensuring a positive experience promoting repeat business and the achievement of personal and professional goals.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Catering and Events Manager Hotel Paseo, and Autograph Collection

Dec 2017 - Current

- As part of the opening team in the hotel, set up the catering and banquets menus, standard operating procedures, diagrams, software, vendors, designs, and more.
- Developed marketing strategies to increase awareness of hotel opening
- Consistent top performer Routinely met and exceeded monthly sales goals
- Established a relationship with local groups, associations, businesses and hotels to determine trends and tendencies of the market and increase sales
- Prospect for new business through different sources to generate new leads and respond to incoming leads on a daily basis
- Detailed and serviced all hotel events working together with AC3 restaurant

Event Coordinator Anaheim Marriott Suites

Mar 2016 - Dec 2017

- Point of contact for signed clients with the primary objective of up-selling through supportive customer service to achieve department revenue goals
- Conduct recurring banquet order meetings with department leaders
- Manage company income by ensuring timely and complete payment from clients.
- Design and create social packages to assist the sales team with potential clients

Account Manager / Event Specialist

Business Expo Center

May 2015 - Dec 2015

- Supervised and planned the execution of logistics and operations for business conferences, trade shows, weddings and special events of up to 800 people
- · Generated new business through inside and outside marketing strategies
- Lead daily sales training on new business policies, procedures and techniques.

Event Coordinator
Paladares, Mexico City
Aug 2013 - May 2014

- Was selected for a mentorship program with the CEO of the company, largest and oldest catering company in Mexico.
- Day of event catering leader at events.

SOFTWARE EXPERTISE

- Microsoft Office
- CI/TY
- MeetingMatrix

EDUCATION

2010 - 2014 Bachelor of Science

Bachelor of Science, Major in Hotel Management

CESSA Universidad

Graduated with Academic Merit

QUICK FACTS

- Interned in Cabo San Lucas as part of the sales team in 2011 then traveled to Barcelona for a 6 month internship in 2013
- Lived for a year in the Czech Republic at age 16 which made me fall in love with learning about different cultures

LANGUAGES

INTERESTS

- Spanish
- French
- Czech
- English

- Travel
 - History
 - Science
- Animals